♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot Roll Call ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
- Pan left.
♪ Gypsy ♪
- Hi, girl.
♪ Tom Servo ♪
- What a cool guy.
♪ Crooooow ♪
- Oh wisecrack er.
♪ You're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
(numerous doors shutting)
- And God bless Joel and Gypsy.
- And all the aliens that
have visited the ship.
- Hi, everybody.
Welcome to Satellite of Love.
When you got a job like ours,
you have to believe
in a higher power.
- [Magic Voice] 30 seconds
to commercial sign.
- And God bless Data and his
really cool robot named Lol.
- And R2-D2 and all the
extras in West-world.
- And RoboCop even though I
thought he got a raw deal,
but it's really
none of my business.
Oh, and all those early versions
that were just there
for comic relief.
- And, uh, ED-209,
though I don't know why
they'd make a robot that
can't walk down stairs.
- And God bless Cherry 3000.
- Oh yeah, and God
bless Galaxina.
Yeah.
- Okay, and who else?
- Oh.
- Do we have to?
- I don't want to.
- Yes, yeah you have to.
- Okay.
- [Crow And Tom]
God bless T wiki.
- [Magic Voice] Commercial
sign in five, four,
three, two...
Commercial sign on.
- Amen.
(upbeat techno-pop)
- Come on, we have
to pray for them.
If we could pray for them,
we can pray for anybody.
- I don't want to pray
for the mad scientists.
- Yeah, Joel, why do we
have to pray for them?
- Well, I think
they're watching,
and they control my oxygen.
- We don't want
you to pray for us.
We want you to pray to us.
Isn't that right, Frank?
- Don't look at me!
I said never look at me!
Mommy, Mommy, ah!
- Frank!
Calm down!
It's time for the invention
exchange again, Joel,
and we'll go first because we've
got a party to go to later.
Well, this summer's
fashions cry out
with jubilant two-inch
armor plating.
Saucy turrets and
shells aplenty.
Can really clear the beaches
this summer with
our new tank tops.
- That's right.
The best beach party ever
was the one at Normandy.
Beach Blanket Bingo...
(goofy noises)
Is now Beach Blanket Bombing
with the latest in
fashion artillery.
- That's right,
shelling on the beach
takes on a whole new meaning.
Let's get in position, Frank.
Ready...
Aim...
Fire.
(shot fired)
Now, let's see how we've done.
- Hey, wait a minute.
I can hear the war.
- Oh, knock that off.
- Oh, oh.
- Now, look at here.
Look, there's
still a little red.
I'm sorry, I can't
give you the bear.
- Damn, why?
- Well, what do you think, Joel?
- Boy, we sure think
differently, thank
goodness, you know.
You know, you guys took
something fun and made it evil
whereas I took something evil
and I'm making it fun.
Check it out, it's the
Tickle Bazooka, all right?
It's for those times
when just a normal tickle
isn't enough.
I based it on the premise
of what the pundits
Fire sign Theater once spoke.
Fightin's out of style.
Fun's where the fear is.
See it's got a feather bayonet
for a hand-to-hand ticking.
(laughter)
- Okay, 'kay, 'kay, cut it out.
- And then if you
really wanna have some
big blast of ballistic hilarity,
there's the Merth
Mortar, let me show ya.
- Uh-oh.
- Brace yourself,
head for cover.
- Okay, smile.
(screaming with
pleasure and laughing)
What do you think?
- That is so neat.
We could base a whole
party around that.
We could all get in
our fuzzy feety pajamas
and jump up and down on the bed.
- Look, the only
party we're going to
is the one where we
dance on your grave.
- Oh, will I be invited?
- You'll be the guest of honor.
(laughing)
Now, tell them about the movie.
I gotta get out of this thing.
I'm chaffing like a bear.
- Well, Joel, this week's
movie is called Catalina Caper,
and it is delightful.
It's a veritable feel good
movie, a lighthearted romp.
A triumph of the human spirit!
Thank you, Tommy
Kirk, for making us
laugh about love...
Again.
And it's got a great theme song.
You're gonna love it.
♪ Never ever ever
steal anything wet ♪
- [Dr Forester] Frank, incoming!
(explosion)
(shouting and laughing)
(alarm sounding)
- [Joel] Movie sign, haha!
(various doors opening)
(laughing and giggling)
- [Joel] That was funny.
- [Crow] (sighs) Oh,
oh fun, that was fun.
- [Tom] Yeah, great fun.
- [Joel] Huh, what gives?
- [Tom] Hmm?
- [Tom And Crow] Huh.
- [Joel] Hmm, interesting.
What's wrong with
this guy's feet?
- [Crow] He has prehensile toes.
- [Tom] What do you supposed
Frogman's legs taste like?
- [Joel] Uh, like Sand Diego
chicken legs, probably?
- [Diver On Screen] Oh.
("Never steal anything
wet" by Carol Connors)
- [Tom] So, what's in the can?
- [Joel] I think it's,
uh, dehydrated water.
- [Tom] Oh
- [Crow] Oh, a scuba film.
- [Joel] Hmm, Jacques Cousteau
meets the Pink Panther.
- [Crow] By this time, my--
- [Joel] Hey, come on, just..
- [Crow] Huh?
You know just lay off.
Okay, sorry.
- [Tom] So what's
a Catalina Caper?
- [Joel] It's one of
those little balls
you find when you
peel and eat shrimp.
- [Tom] Oh.
Sorry, Charlie, only the
best titles are picked.
- [Crow] Starring Tommy Kirk.
Why must Spock die?
- [Tom] Oh, Robert Donner,
I went to his party.
(laughs)
- [Joel] Gee, I wonder what
she's harpin' on about?
- [Crow] Hey, who's this
guy, Jim Begg Sue Casey
Lyle Waggoner Mike Blodgett?
- [Tom] Nice measurements.
36, 2, 85.
(playful music)
- [Crow] I think that fish
is gonna spit up again.
(humming)
- [Joel] Who's afraid
of Venita Wolf anyway?
(laughing)
- [Crow] Charlie, they
cut off my thumbs.
- [Joel] Special guest
star, Peter Mamakos.
- [Tom] Oh Little Richard,
I've heard of him.
He's not as famous
as Peter Mamakos.
- [Crow] Mm-mm.
- [Joel] Oh, he's playing
a trick on that fish.
Oh yeah, feel good about
kickin' a fish's butt.
That's real nice.
(humming)
- [Tom] Hmm, screenplay
written in crayon.
- [Crow] What's Clyde Ware?
Sal Mungeo, rebel
without a gauze.
- [Tom] That's a
Bullwinkle show, isn't it?
- [Joel] Yeah.
- [Crow] Here's something
you'll really like.
- [Tom] Shalom!
(laughing)
- [Joel] Look out!
(laughter)
- [Joel] Wow, that is
really good animation.
(upbeat rock and roll music)
- [Tom] Now I'll set fire
to Walt Whitman books,
then I'll burn the pile
of "Catcher in the Rise".
- [Crow] C'mon, you ho-daddies!
Let's burn some books!
Whee-Hoo!
- [Tom, Joel , Crow] Burn
the witch, burn the witch!
We shall cleanse
the earth with fire.
- [Crow] How do you
know she's a witch?
- [Tom] Oh, these
Klan meetings have
really lightened
up, look at that.
- [Crow] Now that's
what I call art.
Scantily clad women and a
"Huey Lewis and the News"
sound on the radio.
This is the kinda padding
I like to see in a film!
- [Tom] Throw another
Beach Boy on the fire.
Wow.
- [Crow] And so the
Aryan youth dance around
the funeral pyre.
- [Joel] You know, this
is really good sound
and it was before Dolby.
- [Tom] Dolby Gillis?
- [Joel] I dunno.
- [Crow] Meanwhile, in the
dark, impenetrable void,
John-Paul Sartre was
a-movin' and a-groovin'.
- [Tom] No exit, baby.
- [Joel] Oh, looks like
they're in the Night Gallery.
- [Crow] This portrait, a
man who smokes more than
Edward R. Murrow
or Lillian Hellman.
- [Tom] I'm William
Conrad for First Alert.
When you're heading
down to the refrigerator
and the power goes out (laughs).
- [Joel] Hey, it's
Steve Higgins.
- [Tom] Oh, you mean the star
of the Higgins Boys and Gruber
as seen on the Comedy Channel?
- [Joel] Yeah, wow.
- [Crow] This must be
Tommy Kirk's Oscar.
He's so good that they
gave it to him before
they started the film.
He beat out Troy Donahue
and Frankie Avalon.
- [Tom] Huh?
Hey, I beat out Dom DeLuise
and James Coco for this role,
now beat it!
(suspenseful string
quartet music)
(humming)
- [Joel] He's looking
for that string quartet.
- [Crow] An original
Red Skelton!
That's incredibly valuable!
Good night, may god bless.
This painting is blue.
Don't work blue,
it's such a waste.
- [Tom] I'm gonna put
this in a frame that fits.
- [Joel] Gee, it looks
like a garage rag.
- [Tom] Send security.
I'm the one who cracked that
crime at One Potato Two.
I beat out Al Molinaro and
Jesse White for this role.
- [Crow] Oh, that's
a "Family Circus"
from Hank Ketcham's
Bil Keane collection.
- [Joel] Looks
kinda like a Ruben.
- [Tom] Paul Reuben,
I mean Pee-wee Herman?
- [Joel] No.
(laughing)
(suspenseful string
quartet music)
- D'oh!
- Oops.
He broke Tommy's Oscar.
Well, I did the same
thing to his Pulitzer.
(suspenseful string
quartet music)
- Huh?
- What?
Hmmmm?
- [Crow] He's
puttin' it together.
- [Joel] O relax, they'll just
think it's a Rothko now, see?
- [Tom] Yeah, or a
Mondrian, perhaps.
(whistle)
- [Crow] Boy, that's
a big whistle!
You know you to
whistle, don't you?
You just put your lips
together and cut to the boat.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Bangkok oriental city.
Koyaanisqatsi...
A life out of balance.
- [Joel] You know,
this film is a fantasy
'cause you generally
don't see cabs in
Southern California like this.
(laughing)
- [Crow] America's festivious
and well-groomed youth,
living a clean lifestyle,
pumping their clean,
hard-won dollars
into a clean economy,
that is sunny,
colorful Catalina.
(cheerful violin music)
(indistinct chatter)
- [Tom] Oh, look at this.
White people voted the the
best people in the world.
- [Joel] Young, white
males still on top.
- [Crow] NEA denies
Bil Keane Grant.
- [Joel] Oh, looks
like Brutus and Popeye
after SlimFast.
- [Tom] And Olive's
standing right behind 'em.
- [Crow] Hmm.
Not bad.
- [Joel] What's that
supposed to mean?
- I'm goin' on board, Bob.
- [Tom] I know, I can
see it in your eyes.
- It's mother!
Charlie-baby's come
back to the nest.
- Welcome home, delinquent.
- [Crow] Oh, thanks,
but we're felons now.
(laughing)
- Hi, I'm Bob Draper.
The school must've
assigned you as keeper.
- Don Pringle.
- [Crow] Heir to the
potato chip fortune.
- Never seen the
big water before.
I figure a summer on
the island to put a
little juice in the old battery.
- I think you'll like
it if you can take him.
- Liked it?
You should've seen him
comin' up the coast.
I don't think they sell
bikinis in Arizona.
- Well, they sell 'em.
It's what I never saw is
so many trying to cover
so much with so little success.
- [Tom] Thank you,
Winston Churchill.
- I felt the same
way myself once.
It only gets better.
- [Joel] Say...
- Oh, talk about discouraged.
- [Crow] Hmmmm....
- Have you seen the new crop?
- [Crow] And my corn is as
high as an elephant's eye.
- Decisions, decisions.
I've seen three exactly my type!
- [Joel] Yeah, real dumb.
(boat signal)
- [Crow] Whoops, somebody
stole another painting.
- There's the final
boarding whistle.
- Yeah, we'll dig you later.
- I'll be around, if only to
keep you guys out of trouble.
(laughing)
- [Joel] I love this
good-natured ribbing.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Now, what do you
suppose this guy's up to?
- [Joel] Hmmmm.
- [Tom] Oh.
- D'oh!.
- I don't believe it.
- [Crow] He saw Big Jake.
(laughing)
- [Joel] Here, let me
help you up with that.
Say, that gang plank really
gave you a what for, friend.
(laughing)
He shook their "truss".
- [Tom] Okay, cue the
"made-for-tv" music!
♪ Love ♪
exciting and new.
- Smell that air, huh?
Take a look around.
- Air, water--
- [Crow] Air, water.
You're pretty
observant there, pal.
- Nature has provided far
more exhilarating divergence
below deck.
- [Tom] I didn't know you
were holding, my compadre.
- Maybe I made a mistake.
Maybe you're not ready.
- I'm ready, I'm ready!
- [Crow] I think the
Forum will be good for me.
- I plan the agenda.
In Phoenix you showed
me all the ugly glories
of inner-monsters,
cactus and ants.
On Catalina, believe
it man, I am king.
Surfing and girls.
Big game fishing and girls.
Scuba diving...
- [Joel] Guys...
And girls...
- [Tom] He sounds like
Curt Gowdy, doesn't he?
- [Crow] Or Hugh Hefner.
- I'm in your capable hands.
- All right.
And we start the
summer with a bang.
Like we start right
now, below dick.
- [Joel] You mean deck.
- Let me breathe
a little bit, huh?
I've been driving all night.
- Breathe, live...
If Mohammed won't come
to the mountain...
(funky rock and roll music)
- [Crow] I think that's
inappropriate social behavior.
(funky rock and roll music)
- [Tom] Excuse me, I gotta
go invent the Walkman.
After this.
(upbeat electropop)
- [Tom] And so I want
to join the Forum.
- [Joel] Hey...
- [Tom] Hmmmm
- [Joel] Nice railing.
(enchanting violin music)
- [Crow] May I retie your pants?
- Sure is quiet out here.
- [Joel] It was quiet.
- [Crow] What an idiot.
- I've never seen
the ocean before.
- Oh, then you have missed much.
- [Tom] Yeah, that's only
75% of the earth's surface.
- Yes I have.
- There's a whole
world beneath all that.
And there is life, all
sizes, shapes and colors.
- [Crow] What gives, huh?
- We sure could
get hung up on it
tomorrow night on the beach.
- [Tom] Yes, I'm hung
up on it right now.
Help me!
- I dove into the sea and
began swimming under water.
And there was this small fish--
- [Tom] She's beautiful, Joel.
- [Crow] Hey, was she in
the movie, "David and Lisa?"
- [Tom] I think she's pretty.
- And I never saw my
little friend again.
(sighing)
(kissing)
- [Joel] You know, there's
a psychiatrist on board.
I think he can really help you.
- For the weekend,
perhaps longer.
Why?
- Great!
Because would you like
to go swimming with me?
- [Tom] With me and Edie
Sedgwick and Rod LaRod?
- Oh, that would be wonderful,
but I'm afraid that--
- Don baby.
Go get 'em.
- [Tom] Say...
- [Crow] Hey, we're
done with the Forum.
We're Druids now.
- Hidin' the truth.
I can't help whatever
it is I do to 'em.
Come on!
Let's go!
(excited chatter)
(sighs)
- [Tom] I'd like to
make their scene, but
they're a little weird and...
Hey fishy, fishy, fishy.
Come here, little fishy, fishy.
- Hey, let's dig Little Richard
and really turn it on!
- [Crow] Little Richard?
I hate impressionists!
- [Tom] Oh, you're
thinking of Rich Little.
- [Crow] Oh.
- [Joel] Now, pay
attention guys.
This scene is obviously
really important in the film.
This is Little Richard.
- [Crow] Uh-oh.
('Scuba Party' by
Little Richard)
- [Tom] Dig it.
- [Joel] Prince, I hope
you're watching this.
- [Crow] Hey, we have
a chair downstairs
with that upholstery.
- [Tom] It looks
like a coffin lining.
- [Joel] Hey, get the
funk outta my face.
Come on.
Dig it.
- [Crow] Ah, there's really
nothin' we can say about that,
is there?
- [Tom] It's not
during family hour.
- [Joel] Hey look,
it's Alan Seus.
(goofy laughter)
- [Tom] Oops.
- [Joel] He's gettin' seasick.
Hmm. I think I know a
bright, young singer that's
hopped up on
goofballs right now.
- [Crow] Can I see him?
- [Joel] Yes.
And his head's
about ten feet tall.
- [Crow] Hmmmm, that's huge.
- [Tom] I like the
pencil-thin mustache.
- [Crow] Otay.
Hey, it's his band!
- [Joel] Great, next we'll
see Sly Stone with the
Up With People, probably.
- [Tom] Ike Turner
with the Cowsills.
They'll all be in casts.
- [Joel] James Brown and the
Starland Vocal Band maybe?
- [Crow] Yeah.
George Clinton with
the Ray Coniff Singers.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Like this, Mr Richard?
How's this, huh?
- [Crow] Is there a history of
epilepsy in your family, boy?
- [Joel] You know, he's
so hopped up, I think he's
thinking he's at the
Apollo or something.
- [Crow] I like him.
Hey, it's Ron Howard's brother!
- [All] Ben, Ben, Ben.
- [Joel] Hey, wow.
- [Tom] Look's like
cousin Itt with a bob.
- [Crow] A swingin' bob.
- [Tom] Hmm-mmmm.
- [Crow] Little Richard.
The only genuine
talent in this film.
- [Joel] You know, those
dancers are standing
on dumpsters.
Would that make
them white trash?
- [Crow] Uhm...
I'm glad we recycle.
♪ The Nazi Party ♪
- [Tom] Everybody!
- [Joel] You know I'm feelin'
like we were at the dance
thing in Laugh-In, kinda...
(crowd cheers)
- [Crow] Oh, you were
great, now leave.
Out the back door.
- [Joel] Well, it's
just us, Timmy.
When you ever graduate
from Pat Boone University.
- [Crow] So Falco
leaves the Calypso.
And another painting is stolen.
- [Tom] Is this where
they filmd the Boatnix?
It looks really familiar.
- [News Reader] Police
investigations failed to turn up
new clues--
- [Crow] My skull
is an amplifier.
- [Radio Newsreader] Of the
priceless Chu dynasty scroll
from a private Los
Angeles museum.
- [Crow] Yeah, I did it,
I did it, I'm proud man.
- [Radio Newsreader] But police
are stumped at this point.
- [Tom] Hey, you got
puke on my radio.
- [Joel] No, you got
radio on my puke.
Actually I think he's
working on a new script.
- [Tom] Must be
the screenwriter.
- [Joel] Yeah.
- [Tom] Wake up.
- [Tom] Oh, magic
balcony, take me away
from this cookie crowd.
- [Crow] I'm the white
guy who runs this ship.
I can take out this whole
crowd if I wanted to.
I'm that powerful.
Disperse!
- [Joel] It's time to
vacuum the pool, I think.
- [Tom] Hey, you got
room for one more extra?
Wait for me!
- [Joel] Oh, they've got a
fat dumpy guy in this already.
- [Tom] Oh, I'm sorry.
- [Crow] They're
diving for chum.
- [All] Gun it, Gun it!
- [Tom] Gun it now.
Chop 'em up.
- [Crow] Petticoat Junction.
(screaming excitedly)
- [Joel] Hey, what gives?
He's the guy with the implant.
- [Crow] Carol?
Uh, Carol, uh, Carol, uh Carol?
- [Joel] Harvey?
- Carol?
- [Crow] How's your little fish?
- [Joel] We have a proper love.
(humming)
- [Tom] I got your
stick, Mr. Luthor.
- [Joel] Oh.
- [Tom] Oh, would
you give me that?!
- [Joel] Sorry.
- [Tom] Oh, I'm too tired
tired to even do one of
my famous pratfalls.
- [Crow] I'm all hurtin'
and hot and hurt and stuff.
- [Tom] Now guys, just
sit right back and
you'll hear a tale.
(laughing)
Crete, ancient civilization.
- [Tom] Mykonos,
modern civilization.
(sighing)
- [Crow] Mel Brooks, Anne
Bancroft and Dom DeLuise
in Boatniks 2.
- Home run for the bases
loaded, just like we planned.
- [All] Oh, shut up.
(slurping)
- Lawrence, we're
really proud of you.
You're a credit to
your profession.
- [Crow] Village idiot.
- I do the best I can
with what I've got.
- [Tom] Which isn't
all a helluva lot.
- Let's go downstairs
and I'll show you.
- Tad is below.
- I'm afraid our son wouldn't
approve of our little--
- [Crow] Your son?
What is this?
Who's afraid of Virginia Woolf?
- I know what you mean--
- [Tom] It's not
your son, George.
- You just can't trust a kid
who don't follow baseball.
- [Joel] Or trust a guy
with a dumb Crayola hat.
Hey, it's filled with M,M's.
- [Crow] Hmm. Neat.
- [Joel] Long ones.
- [Tom] Now let's see here.
You are a child of the
universe, no less than
the trees and...
- [Joel] It's "Desiderata!"
- What do you think, Anne?
- [Crow] It's a Howard
Johnson place mat.
I don't think you won
the riddle contest.
- Well, with the
equipment we have below,
it shouldn't take long.
- [Tom] Say.
- I should have the
duplicate finished
in less than 24 hours.
- Excellent.
- [Joel] She's somethin'.
- We're a great little team.
- [Joel] Ah, shut up.
- [Crow] Yeah, not enough
for an infield, but...
It's the William
Burroughs figurehead.
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Even they make me sick.
- Hey, why two?
- One for the genuine,
one for the duplicate.
- [Tom] And one
for the little girl
who lives down the lane.
- [Crow] Jodie Foster?
- [Tom] Yeah.
- [Joel] Now we know
the entire plot.
Thanks a lot.
- Hey, have you contacted
our fat, Greek pigeon yet?
- [Tom] Hmm?
- Our friend, Lakopolous
arrived last night.
- [Crow] He's the topolous.
- You know, I hear he's got
a whole castle filled with
stolen art treasures,
stashed away in Switzerland.
Nerdspopolous.
- How come a millionaire
like Dino Lakopolous
wants to be a crook?
- [Joel] 'Cause
he's unscrupolous.
- One needs a profession to
procure ones taste, Lawrence.
- Oh, I see.
- [Joel] Can I
write that for you?
Oh.
- First, we show
him the picture.
- He okay's 'em, right?
- Right.
Then we slip in the
phoney scroll that
you're gonna paint tonight.
- [All] Then Donald goes in
where the others have been.
- Then you'll return the
original to its rightful owner.
- [Crow] And then return
that shirt to Robin Williams.
- I mean, how come
we can't keep it?
- We certainly can't keep it!
That would be dishonest!
- [Tom] Oh.
- Well, the deal we're
pulling on Lakopolous
ain't exactly kosher, you know.
- [Tom] Oh, hold the mail.
- Lakopolous is a proud thief.
That's the only way
he'll do business.
It's expected one
would try to cheat him.
- [Tom] Like Nixon.
- Arthur, you've outdone
yourself this time.
Oh, you're simply
glowing with imagination.
- [Crow] That's sweat.
- Oh dear, I'm really
very proud of you.
- Thank you, dearest.
I must admit I do have a
flair for this sort of thing.
- [Tom] Alcoholism?
- True, true.
(laughing)
- [Crow] Bet he won't fall.
(amusing music)
- [Tom] Oh, well we
better beat it, guys.
- [Crow] Beat what, a--
(laughing)
- [Tom] It kills me.
(several doors closing)
- Joel, could you
tell us about this
thing called the Sixties?
- Yeah.
I'm amused and fascinated
by such an environment
that the beautiful,
Creepy Girl existed in.
- Well, I was just a little
kid when it happened,
but I can tell you
guys what I remember.
- Okay.
- Well, you're so much
older than you're younger
than that now.
- Yeah, whatever Crow.
Anyway, Cambot Could
you roll that music?
Yeah, cool, okay.
- Well, it was a lot simpler
time back then, you know?
I'll give you an example.
It wasn't uncommon at all for
your mom to come and serve you
a great big charbroiled steak
while she smoked and drank
a Tab and made your dad
another Manhattan for the road.
And that was just breakfast.
- Oh, go on.
- Yeah, there were
seat belts in cars--
- But nobody used them.
Pre-sweetened cereal,
subliminal messages,
people smoked openly
on The Tonight Show.
- Hey, tell us about
the Rat Pack again.
- Oh, okay.
Well, as you know, Frank
Sinatra was Chairman of the
Board and everybody
else filed on in line.
Except for Jerry Lewis.
He had to have a falling
out with Dean Martin,
and they already had chosen
Joey Bishop to be their
comic relief already, so
he was kind of outta luck.
But Dean was tall and tanned
and quick with a song.
And he just had to say
the word and cuckoo chicks
would file on up to
the hospitality suite.
And massage Peter Lawford's
neck and make everybody
groovy drinks while they
took important phone calls
from places like Palm
Springs and the White House.
Until it was time for Frank
Sinatra, the Chairman of the
Board to come out of the
sauna and he'd say the words
and the dollies
would go take a nap.
- Subliminal messages.
- Oh.
Tell us about the rabbits, Joel.
- Yeah, that's a good one.
- That's okay.
Meanwhile, in the Windy City,
Hugh Hefner was cooking up
his own groovy scene in the
aptly named PlayBoy Mansion.
- Oh wow.
- There was George Kennedy
and George Hamilton and
Tony Curtis and Bill Bixby
were all in his court.
Sophisticated men who
knew their raquet and--
- I think you're
swingin' it a-high.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, anyway, there was
like Twiggy and Abby and
Peter, Paul and Mary,
Dionne, Donovan, Melony,
Abraham Martin and
John, you know?
- And so they just went by
their first names like that?
- Yeah, like you, Crow.
- Hey.
And there were typewriters,
but nobody used them.
And women were called girls.
- Wow.
- And businessmen wore
double-breasted suits,
had double chins, drank
double Bourbons, straight
and no chaser, before,
during and after important
business meetings
and summit talks.
Everybody believed what
the President said and
why shouldn't they?
Sexually provocative
humor wasn't on TV, it was
on cocktail napkins and
we liked it that way.
Toys had metal edges and
little pieces that were
breakable and would
fit into your mouth.
They would take and make
playground equipment
out of stainless steel and
haul it up on the asphalt
where you could get hurt.
Parents were actually
told to spank their kids.
Why, my mom actually made
me go and get the belt.
You know, in front of company.
And that was really
frustrating, because once they
- Joel!
made me take a bath
in the front yard--
- Joel!
- Why can't you be like
everyone else and just
remember the good
things about the '60s?
- Yeah, like Woodstock.
- Oh, the Woodstock,
great, okay.
No Joel, you can't
go to Woodstock.
You're nine years old.
We're going to the opening
of the new Century store.
Oh yeah, on Echo Lane.
Three days of peace,
love and pizza rolls.
We're gonna buy you a shopping
cart for your birthday, Joel.
- Uh people, Joel's
in a lotta pain.
We'll be right back.
- Oh boy, Peter from Acts
moved freely among men.
Oh, did I mentioned that
there were drugs at that time?
And then...
(upbeat electropop music)
(church bells ringing)
- [Joel] Yeah, and the only
shoes they had were PF Flyers
and Keds and that was it.
Nothing, no pumps, no nothin'.
- [Tom] Okay, okay Joel.
Okay, you can cool it now.
- [Crow] You okay?
- [Joel] Yeah.
- [Tom] Hey, look at the
prow on that steamer.
Let's climb aboard.
- [Joel] Wow.
- [Tom] Ahoy, matey.
- [Joel] Hello, Betty.
Yeah, that's one of my chicks.
- Turn to, turn to, you idiot!
- [Tom] Turn to what?
- [Crow] The Comedy Channel.
(laughing)
- [Crow] A little
promo there, gang.
- [Tom] Woowwww.
(laughing)
- Hello, hello.
- Hiya, Shaol.
- Shall we have breakfast
at the club dear?
- That would be nice.
- [Joel] I wet myself.
Ew.
- [Tom] Thank goodness this
briefcase is a personal
flotation device.
(mimics trombone)
- [Crow] I love that trombone.
- [Joel] Welcome to White
Island, acting like we deserve
this kind of lifestyle.
- [Tom] Only the best-looking
girls get to be starfish.
- Chuck, it's great
to have you home!
- [Crow] Hey, it's
great to see you!
What's your name?
- [Tom] Hi, wanna trade hair?
(goofy laugh)
- You sure made a
scene out there.
- It's all your fault.
You weren't supposed to
be here until tomorrow.
- We finished our exams
a split a day early.
- [Crow] Hey, how are
things in the Fatherland?
- [Tom] Mom got hung up on
the tennis girl with the club.
- This must be John Pringle?
- You named him
right, Miss Bunny.
- [Tom] I understand
your ruffles have ridges.
(laughing)
- Chuck mentioned you were
coming in his last letter.
We'll try to make your summer
as eventful as possible.
- [Joel] Oh wow.
- Well, I'm prepared to
defend myself against anything
you might have said
about me, if I have to.
- [Crow] He said
you were a jerk.
- Something tells me apologies
are in order, Miss Bunny.
- Miss Bunny?
- Oh.
- [Crow] No, McHale, what
the hell are you doin'?
- [Tom] That guy looks
like Ralph on Green Acres,
doesn't he?
(birds chirping in the distance)
- Are you folks all right?
- Oh yeah, sure.
We're fine, fine.
All except my assistant.
He's a little wet.
I left him on board.
- I'm awfully sorry.
That was pretty stupid of me.
- Oh, think nothing
of it, young lady--
- [Crow] You are
blonde after all.
- This is my wife,
Anne, our son Tad.
- Charlie Moss.
My sister Tina and ---
- [All] Tad. Jean. Tad. Tom.
Paul. Bob. Carol. Ted. Alice.
- [Joel] Stop it!
- Isn't that the Sloanes'
yacht you're using?
- Yes, as a matter
of fact, it is.
- Oh, the Sloanes.
We met the Sloanes in
Monte Carlo last season.
Charming people.
- [Tom] Why, so gracefully.
- When they learned of our
plans to spend the summer here
at Catalina, they
insisted that we have
the use of their yacht.
- Is this your first trip here?
- Well, yes.
We haven't had much
opportunity to visit your
little treasure island.
However, we are interested
in learning all there
is to know about
treasure, aren't we, Anne?
(laughter)
- [Crow] Hey, I just
became a Mormon.
- I'm with you, Miss Bunny.
- Tad, why don't you come along?
We're gonna split with a
boat for some scuba diving.
- Oh, but of course.
Oh that's a very
kind invitation.
Tad's been cooped up aboard
ship since we arrived.
- [Crow] Tied to a mast.
- It would give you a chance
to enjoy yourself, son.
Meet some people your own
age, like Miss Bunny here.
- [Tom] Get away from
your effeminate father.
- Live a little!
- No thanks.
Next time around?
- [Joel] Not nearly enough
beautiful women for me.
- Dad, could I see
you for a minute?
- Certainly, Son.
- Excuse me, dear.
I'm going up to the hotel
to get another sunhat.
- [Joel] You know,
dad, mom's really hot.
- Dad, why did we
come to Catalina?
- Came to enjoy ourselves, why?
- Whenever you and mother
come to enjoy yourselves,
it means you're involved in
some kind of a shady deal.
- [Tom] Oh, I know you've
been hanging around with that
Dave Delgado guy.
- I'm glad your mother
isn't here to listen--
- When you talk like that,
I know you're up to no good.
- [Crow] And when you smell
like that, somebody must die.
- What kind of a shady deal
could we possibly be involved
in on a small island like this?
- I don't know, but whatever
it is, you and mother
are right smack in
the middle of it.
- Ted, I give you my word.
Your mother and I
are here on a holiday
and for no other reason.
Now I'm starved.
Let's get something to eat.
- [Joel] Yeah, and when you
give that take to the camera,
what do you expect?
♪ Oh my dad I love him so ♪
- [Joel] Oh, you guys,
this is gonna be funny.
Now, just let it play out.
I wanna get all the
great humor in this.
- [Tom] Get ready to laugh.
- [Crow] Heck of a
walk from the mainland.
- [Tom] Oooooohhh.
- [Crow] And then it
gets funny, right?
- [Joel] Hmmmm.
- [Tom] Oh, well.
- [Crow] Well maybe now.
- [Tom] Is that the funny part?
- [Joel] I guess.
- [Charlie] That's the place!
Okay, Miss Bunny,
drop the anchor!
- [Crow] I heard he did.
- [Tom] We need a
new shower curtain.
- Wow, you don't leave
much to the imagination.
- [Tom] I don't have one.
- Every do any diving, Don?
- [Joel] Oh, yeah.
- Not quite.
- There's a trick to it.
Just remember, one thing--
- [Tom] You'll be under water.
- Breathe normally,
but through your mouth,
not your nose.
- [Charlie] Bottoms up!
- [Crow] He's
always sayin' that.
We don't know why.
- Hey, it looks like a gap.
- You'd better use the ladder.
- [Tom] Oxygen.
- I'm on the diving
team, remember?
- Congratulations.
Now use the ladder.
- [Joel] But I said I
was on the diving team.
- [Tom] It's the Pueblo.
- It's all right, just kids.
- Very interesting.
- [Crow] But stupid.
What is it, Mr. Lakopolous?
Let me have a look.
- Don't get excited, Borman.
Too young for you.
- That isn't fair.
- You keep your
mind on the ship.
I'll take care of
everything else.
- [Tom] An exchange student.
- [Tom] (talks
incoherently with lisp)
- Unfortunately, Duval
is a thief, a clever one.
(squeaky noises)
- We must trust no one
and be very careful.
- [Crow] And remember
something else too.
And object in motion,
tends to stay in motion,
unless acted upon by
an unbalanced force.
Now, get out.
- [Tom] Doesn't sound
very Greek, does he?
- And a very stupid one.
You are the purported
art expert I can replace.
- [Joel] Okay, Daddy Warbucks.
- I promise you
a long walk home.
- [Tom] Then I'll
kill you again.
- [Crow] Should I go put the
horse's head in my bed again?
- [Tom] Hi Kaiser Wilhelm,
you kooky monarch.
(giggles)
- Lakopolous is still out there.
- [Joel] Hmmmm,
is that your hand?
- You know, I'd give a
month's pay to know why
he's got such a sudden
interest in California waters.
- [Joel] Five bucks?
- Sure must be nice.
Have all that bread,
cruise around the world
on your own yacht--
- [Crow] Eat all the
fruit, throw away the rind.
♪ Goin' out to Eden ♪
- Those vultures that
work for him will pick
his little world clean.
- [Crow] Nice analogy.
I knew I hired you for
something, Rod Mckuen?
- [Tom] Let's break for chow.
- [Joel] They are a
couple of salty tars.
- What do I do now?
- Pull down your face mask.
- [Tom] Pull down your what?
- Can you breathe all right?
(mumbles incoherently)
- Now duck under
and swim around.
But stay close to the surface.
- [Crow] Wow, this is
the weirdest Lamaze class
I've ever seen.
- [Joel] It's all blue
and it's wet and stuff.
- You okay, or do
you wanna cop out
while you're still ahead?
- My nose won't stop breathing.
- Let's try it again.
Take a couple of deep
breaths through your mouth.
- [Joel] Ah.
- [Tom] Oh, that's
this thing, right?
The slit in my face?
- But not this time in two
minutes, take it without me.
- Ready to give it a try?
- I'm with you.
- Hang on to my waist.
- Anything you say, teacher.
- [Joel] Hey, hey.
- Down boy, you've
got the wrong sport.
- When does it become
the right sport?
- [Crow] When ESPN merges
with the PlayBoy channel.
Now get under water!
- Remember, breathe
through your mouth.
- [Joel] Not through your hand.
(magical music)
- [Crow] By this time my--
(throat clearing)
I'm sorry, that
was me, I'm sorry.
- [Tom] Hit some Jacques
Cousteau instead, will ya?
I wonder what would happen
if I turn off the air?
- [Joel] Say, I hear Ivan Tors
is casting a new adventure
show in the Keys with a dolphin.
- [Tom] What happens
if I see a leviathan?
- [Joel] (incoherent
underwater babbling)
(upbeat techno-pop)
- [Tom] Time to
impress some people.
Then I'll go out and start a
line of clothes called "Polo".
Oh, I look like Phil
Harris, don't I?
- [Crow] He'll cast
us in Excalibur.
- He knows all you've
gotta know about
killing and things like that.
He's got it up here.
Do you know that he knows
the batting average of
every white stocking
player of the 1876 season?
- [All] Oh, shut up.
- But in broad
daylight and so soon.
Oh boy...
I should have stayed
in real estate.
(xylophone tone)
- [Tom] Oh, that's my watch.
It does that every quarter hour.
- [Crow] Oh, it
hurts when I think.
Let's see.
Oh, the line, yeah.
Right, the rabbit goes
around the hole and then it
comes out the other
(mumbles incoherently)
- [Tom] Meanwhile, on Bruce
Wayne's stately yacht...
- Hey, there's a boat out there.
Do you think that's him?
- [Joel] It's us, you fool.
It's an exterior shot.
- Well, if you ask me, we're
stickin' our necks way out
playing ball in his park.
- [Tom] And you don't
even have a neck.
- How come we gotta show the
real scroll to Lakopolous' men?
- One thine you must learn,
Lawrence, is that you show
the genuine item
to bait the hook.
Proving to the buyer
that you have it
is one of the
distasteful but necessary
things about this business.
- [Crow] Tell me
when you're done.
- Maybe he won't show up anyway.
- Borman specified the
cove away from the harbor
for the rendezvous.
I doubt that he'll miss it.
- [Tom] Now get away
from me, little man.
- Patience, Lawrence. One other
thing that you must learn.
Now draw up anchor.
(xylophone tone)
- [Tom] Oh, there's that
watch of mine again.
- Where?
- Will you get outta here.
(incoherent mumbling)
- [Joel] Okay, all right.
- [Crow] Great.
- [Joel] Remember that
last time we were a little
disappointed?
- [Joel] I think now, we're
gonna see a scene that's
ripe with comic
possibilities, all right?
The real mechanics of comedy.
Tragedy tomorrow...
- [All] Comedy tonight.
- [Crow] The Jacques Tati
of the boating world.
- [Joel] Yup.
- [Tom] Monsieur
Hulot in Catalina.
- [Crow] You know
what's gonna be funny?
He's wearing corduroy.
- [Tom] Right.
Gonna get doused.
- [Crow] This is...
This is the funny right here.
- [Tom] Uh-oh.
He's gonna catch his
foot in the rope.
Oh no.
Number 27, the old boat
in the anchor trick.
- [Crow] Uh, but
where's the funny?
- [Joel] Hey!
(laughing)
- [Tom] Didn't come out
of his tuck in time.
Russian judge gives him a three.
(gurgling)
- [Joel] Really
wasn't funny at all.
That was kinda stupid actually.
- [Tom] Hi, I'm the bad guy.
Remember me?
(dramatic orchestra music)
(evil laugh)
- [Crow] Hey, there's
a world out there!
- [Tom] Hmmmm?
Candygram.
- [Crow] I am death.
- [Joel] Have you ever
read our Watchtower?
- On time, hey gentlemen?
Where's the scroll?
- Did you bring the money?
- Mr Lakopolous is
not a stupid man.
- [Joel] Sure he drools and
sings camp songs, but...
- [Crow] Gee, it's hard to take
him seriously in that suit.
- [Joel] Yeah.
- [Tom] Uh, you're
soaking in it.
(laughing)
- [Joel] So you swim
around here much?
Weren't you a little
hard on the fat guy?
- [Tom] Yeah.
(whistling)
- [Crow] Hmmmm...
Don't you have a line?
Oh, uh, here he is.
- Look, the water fuzz.
- [Crow] Water fuzz?
- [Tom] Yet some
call them water pigs.
- Oh no, you don't.
- [Crow] Oh yes, I do.
(struggle)
- [Tom] Uh-oh.
And in she goes.
(dramatic violin music)
- [Joel] Eh, please, not me.
Huh? What?
Spinner, Paddlefoot!
Quick, Clutch is in trouble!
- [Miss Bunny] How did
you like it down there?
- Once I get the hang of
it, I may give up the desert
and rattlesnakes for life.
- [Tom] Yeah.
- [Joel] Water fuzz.
They're wet, they care.
Tonight's episode, "Death Ahoy"
- [Tom] Yo-ho-ho.
And a bottle of death.
- [Crow] Tinker, taylor,
solider, dead man.
- [Joel] Michael, row
your murder ashore.
- [Tom] Hallelujah.
- [Tom] No Timmy, no, no!
Darn fool kid.
- [Crow] Skippy's in trouble!
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Ah, you just ate.
Be careful down there.
- [Crow] Well, they're gone.
Let's form a girl group.
(dramatic violin music)
- [Tom] Oh, looks like
somebody's swabbed the deck
with somebody's butt.
(laughing)
- [Tom] (mimics on-screen music)
- [Crow] Along about that
time, the old Duke boys
got a little trouble
comin' their way,
in the form of Mister Skinman.
- [Tom] Huh?
It is cold down there, look.
- [Joel] Greetings,
I come from the...
Huh?
- [Tom] Come on, come on!
Give it here, baby.
(struggle)
- [Joel] (mimicking speaking
incoherently under water)
- [Tom] Must get
back to Rylos Five.
- [Crow] This must
be Wetside Story.
- [Tom] Join me in my
depth of dust (evil laugh).
- [Crow] Yes, it's
synchronized swimming on ESPN.
The wet network.
- [Tom] Help me, Cecil!
Help me!
I'm comin', Beany Boy!
(mimicking talking
incoherently under water)
(dramatic orchestral music)
- [Crow] I will kill him!
- [Joel] I'm going to give
you such a water-wedgie,
you're not gonna ever forget.
- [Tom] An aqueous snuggie!
- [Crow] I can't
believe he did that!
I just came over to say hello.
What would make a guy do that?
- [Tom] Here, breathe from me.
Take life from me, please.
- [Joel] Oh look, they're
standing four abreast.
You know, it's--
- [Crow] Oh, please.
- [Joel] I'm sorry.
(dramatic cello music)
- [Tom] Oh, we'll
just stand here,
'cause they're men
and and we're not.
- Take 'em to the other
boat, it's closer.
- [Crow] If it's so
close, why can't we see it
in this shot?
- [Tom] We don't
wanna be involved.
- [Joel] Gee, what a wimp.
Can't even take a seasoned
diver with a knife.
Boy.
- [Crow] I'm afraid you boys
will find only evil here.
- [Tom] I had 'em, Charlie.
I'm tellin' ya, I
coulda killed 'em.
He took my thumbs, Charlie.
- What happened?
- Well, I'm not sure--
- [Tom] Well, I starred
in theater, moved
on to summer stock
and now I'm in this film, why?
- Held a gun on me
and he took my wallet,
I tried to stop him, we scuffled
and he went overboard.
- He didn't have any
wallet when I saw 'em.
- [Crow] It was eel skin.
Happy now, croonboy?
- You see, there was nothing
of importance in the wallet.
- [Tom] You see, 'cause
I'm lying my socks off.
- No, never.
- Where did he come from?
- Probably swam, uh,
out from shore, I guess.
- [Joel] Ah, sure, yeah
that's it, that's right.
- [Tom] Yeah sure.
- [Joel] I'm kinda skeptical.
- Seems like an awful
long ways to swim
just for a few dollars.
- [Joel] Yeah.
- Last time I saw him, he
was heading out to sea.
- [Crow] How would you know?
You were drowning.
- Well, it doesn't
really matter.
It's all over now and I'm
very grateful this young man
didn't get hurt.
- Come on, Tiger.
- [Tom] Don't call me
that here, Bunny, please.
- [Joel] Uh, tanks.
- Ooh.
- I tried to.
- I knew we shouldn't have
brought the real one out here.
He knows!
We just struck out.
- Larry, would you
please settle down?
- [Crow] Get married, have
some kids and take that
ridiculous hat off.
- I'm a little concerned
with the problem at hand.
We've got to get that case
back before Lakopolous sends
his divers back for it.
Now, I know the scroll
case is water tight,
but if we lose it,
we really strike out.
- [Tom] Think that's funny, huh?
Shoot yourself in the leg.
I'll be right back.
- [Joel] All done
throwin' up, Spunky?
- I didn't know you cared.
- I don't.
- [Crow] We're gonna
bigger boat, right?
- Yacht party?
- You're really new here.
Haven't you ever heard of one?
- Is it anything like
a rattle snake hunt?
- [Tom] What the
heck does that mean?
- [Joel] He's high.
- And I thought
you were getting an
education in Arizona.
- [Tom] Hey, we gotta split.
- [Joel] Yeah, kids
just beat me up a lot
when I was a kid.
- [Crow] Really?
- [Joel] Yeah.
No, in the movie.
- [Crow] Oh.
- You do have a lot to learn.
They swing.
Really swing.
(upbeat techno pop)
(crying)
- Creepy Girl.
Oh, Creepy Girl.
Little, Creepy Girl.
(crying)
- Geez, what's wrong, Tom Servo?
You look as upset and
down-trodden as a little robot
with inarticulate
limbs can look.
- Oh, it's Creepy Girl, Joel.
I just met a girl
named Creepy Girl.
And suddenly I find--
- I smell a song comin' on.
(crying)
♪ Oh, Creepy Girl ♪
♪ Lyle Wagner's a total jerk ♪
♪ Second only to Tommy Kirk ♪
♪ Could you find
it in your heart ♪
♪ to love a bot like me-e-e ♪
♪ That fishy story you tell ♪
♪ Always makes me sleepy ♪
♪ But that's just what I get ♪
♪ For dating a girl
that's creepy ♪
♪ My Creepy Girl ♪
- Oh, "C", it's for that
feeling of uncertainty
for not quite knowing what
ethnic group you're from.
"R" it's for the gifts you
give me every time you smile.
The first "e" is for, uh,
well, I don't really know,
but the second "e" is
really a grammatical thing,
'cause otherwise it
would be "Crepy Girl"
and where would that leave us?
The "p" is definitely
not for platonic
and "y" because I love you.
♪ My Creepy Girl ♪
Oh, what are you, Creepy Girl?
Are you French, Italian or one
of those swarthy gypsy types?
(laughing)
Well, your accent suggests
a romance language,
but I can't be sure.
Oh, and we can definitely
rule out a Trumanic language.
But it's okay, I am a
bot without a country.
All I know is that I love you.
I wanna shout it from
the mountaintops.
Uh, but I'd have to
get back down to earth
and actually climb a mountain.
Or they can just drop me off
on a mountain, I don't care.
That would be okay,
because I just need you.
♪ My Creepy Girl ♪
♪ Won't you be mi-eh-ine ♪
♪ I'll give you
scrolls and fish and ♪
♪ Tinker toys and wi-ee-ine ♪
♪ I'll ditch these guys ♪
♪ If you'll be my Creepy Girl ♪
♪ Be mine ♪
♪ Before movie sign ♪
(alarm bells)
♪ Oh, ooohhhh ♪
(various doors opening)
- [Crow] Say, she's got
a Rorschach Swimsuit.
- [Joel] What are you
seeing there, Crow?
- [Tom] I see the Creepy Girl.
- [Joel] Oh, I see cookie pants.
- [Crow] I see trouble.
(funky music)
- [Tom] Come on and do the dork.
- [Crow] Hey, nice little
boat they landed there.
Except they killed that
thing they roasted there.
- [Tom] Everybody, get down.
- [All] Ouch, owie, ow, ow,
hot, hot, still hot here.
Nails, staples, ow, ouch.
- [Joel] This is
the movie that...
One of the movies that shaped
middle America's sexuality.
Deformed it.
- [Crow] Deformed it.
- [Tom] I could say
something else, but I won't.
It's cold out there.
- This is the place.
- [All] Hell.
- In Arizona they
call this a mirage.
(funky music)
- [Joel] They call it
drug-induced in hysteria.
- [Tom] Yeah.
- Charlie!
- Well, baby's come home.
- [Tom] Hmm-mmm.
- Yeah, that guy
must have something.
- [Tom] Yeah, he doesn't shop at
"Members only" or "Wards".
- [Crow] Well, when
in Rome, or Athens.
- Hi Charlie!
- It's been a long,
cold winter, Charlie.
- [Tom] What does that mean?
- Yeah.
- [Joel] Get over there,
I need some more chicks.
- [Tom] What did you
say your name was?
Yeah, I'm casting Caligula
this summer, so come on down.
- [Crow] This film was funded
by the Utah Film Board.
(funky music)
- [Joel] Hey, she's got a
shaggy diaper that leaks.
(laughing)
- [Crow] Get it away from me.
- [Tom] Hey, it's
Ed Begley Junior.
(mimics karate fighting)
- [Crow] Hey, she lost
a bone in her neck.
Look at that flappin'
around like that.
- [Joel] Come on,
keep 'em comin'.
Monkey love, pile on me.
(growling)
- [Crow] That must
be what they mean by
five easy pieces.
- [Tom] Oh, please.
- [Joel] Looks like
the cast of "Zoom".
♪ Come on and zoom,
zoom, zooma, zoom ♪
- [Crow] Nice
tablecloth there, eh?
- [Joel] Yeah, very practical.
(barking)
- Arsenio Hall!
- My posse!
(crowd cheering)
(funky music)
- [Joel] Oh boy.
- [Tom] Joel, was this
before coco butter?
- [Joel] Yeah, I think so.
("There's a new World"
by The Cascades)
- [Crow] Shirts by the
Renaissance Festival!
and King John, who
invites you to come down
and see Robin Hood
and Little John;
two never-was actors
performing bad skits.
- [Tom] And bad music.
These guys are horrible.
(off-key humming)
- [Tom] I'm gonna
quit this band and
start a career in music.
- [Joel] Couple of
cheese eaters there.
- [Crow] Yeah.
- [Tom] Oh, please.
- [Crow] Bee Gees go badder.
- [Tom] Worse.
♪ And I haven't learned
the words to say ♪
- [Joel] Hey look, I'm 60.
(laughing)
Yeah, I'm still rockin'.
Watch me.
- [Tom] Yeah, tune
in, turn on, throw up.
(off-key humming)
- [Crow] Now I know why drugs
were so big in the '60s.
(laughing)
You need' em.
♪ I won't ♪
♪ Pretend ♪
♪ To sing ♪
♪ While the girls prance
around in their BVD's ♪
(laughing)
- [Joel] What do you think?
- [Crow] Yeah.
- [Tom] Pretty bad.
- [Crow] Lyrics
by Aldous Huxley.
(laughing)
♪ Hey most of these
lyrics are in A ♪
- [Crow] I think they sent
the wrong people to Nashville.
- [Joel] You know, could
somebody do us a favor
and push that guy's amp
in the water, maybe?
♪ We can't sing ♪
♪ There's a concept,
it's called harmony ♪
♪ There's another concept,
it's called obscurity ♪
- [Crow] Ah, look at
those stupid legs.
They're stupid lookin'.
They're not real-lookin' at all.
- [Tom] Look like puppets.
(clears throat)
- [Joel] Sieg heil!
- Hey, anybody who
wants, let's split
to the beach for volleyball.
- [Tom] Eh, you go
ahead, that's okay.
- [Crow] Hey, we're pickin'
up the sports channel.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Darn and
I forgot my shins.
- [Joel] Oh, the
other kids hate me.
- [Crow] One Adam-12, see the
man whose shins were stolen.
- Shoulda been on
board the scuba party.
You missed all the action.
- I heard what happened.
I wanted to say thanks
for helping Dad.
- [Crow] I had to see the man.
See the man, Coroner
Willmont and Crowley.
- That doesn't matter.
I appreciate what you did.
- [Tom] I'll let you
use my shins, deal?
- Lyle!
- [Joel] Hey, what did I do?
(sexy trumpet music)
- [Tom] Oh, Joel, it's her!
- Whose that?
- [Tom] It's my
Creepy Girl, Joel.
(crying)
- [Crow] Finally, a sultry
woman with a nice body.
It's about time.
- [Tom] Watch who
you're talkin' about.
It's my girl.
- [Joel] Come on,
follow the leader.
- [All] D'oh!
- [Crow] She's not too happy.
- [Tom] Dibs, I call dibs.
She's mine.
Back off, you clowns.
I'll take you all out.
- [Joel] Let's try
walkin' like her.
(purring)
- [Tom] Slow burn comin' up.
- Are you coming, Don, or not?
- [Tom] Well, you'll do nicely.
Let's go have little
Marty Milners.
- [Crow] Remember what I said
about the last man on earth?
Well, it's time.
- Are you on a catch like I am?
- [Crow] You mean from reality?
- Yes, why?
- You don't catch on
very fast, do you?
- [Crow] What do you mean?
- I'm afraid I'm not
used to the speed.
- Aaahh, don't tell
me you're a drag too.
- [Tom] Just a drag
queen from Mardi Gras.
- Do you think you can
handle a beach party?
- I think it's worth a try.
- Okay, let's go.
- Uh, what about him?
- We're not engaged.
- [Tom] Hmm.
Loose morals, huh?
I get it.
- [Tom] Meanwhile, on ESPN.
- [Joel] Everybody,
ditch the little guy.
- [Tom] Uh, so the
game's over, huh?
Hey, hey, hey, come back here!
Hey, what's the
matter with me, huh?
Bad breath or something?
- [Joel] Uh, I guess I'm
kinda messed up after all.
Nobody likes me.
- Here.
- [Tom] There she is!
(gasps)
- Over here!
- [Tom] Is she okay?
I'm goin' out to get her, Joel.
Quick, come and get her.
- Well, do you
plan to stay there
and watch me die of pneumonia?
- [Crow] Well, both actually.
- [Tom] Oh no.
Oh, I can't help her, Joel.
- [Crow] Gee, what a nice guy.
- [Tom] Uh, excuse
me, can I have my...
Uh, where are you goin'?
I'm sorry, I'm gonna
need that back.
Excuse me?
Don't go too far with that.
It's my windbreaker.
I paid five bucks
for that at Wards.
Please.
- Can I help?
- No thank you.
Turn around.
- [Tom] Oh, thank you god.
- [Crow] Hmm, he's
kinda caught between
a rock and a hard place.
(clearing throat)
- Not yet.
(zip)
- [Joel] Done?
- Sorry, I didn't
mean to embarrass you.
- [Tom] Isn't this movie enough?
- Ah, this is no
time to be delicate.
It's a good thing
you stayed behind.
I was ready to
sacrifice my modesty.
- [Tom] Oh, we'll
get to that, my love.
- [Crow] Oh, Joel,
I have a question.
- [Joel] Yeah?
- [Crow] What happened
to the treasure hunt
part of the film?
- [Joel] Well, the
movie's only half over.
Maybe we'll learn
somethin' about it still.
- Still looking for
your little fish?
- Oh, you remembered?
- [Tom] Oh yeah, your
deep-seated psychosis?
Of course.
- We talked on the boat.
That is, I should say I talked.
But we never really met.
I'm Katrina Corelli.
- [Crow] And I'm
cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs.
- Nice to meet you though.
- [Tom] So, you're here
on an outpatient basis?
I like that.
- Your friends certainly
know how to enjoy themselves.
- They're a fun group.
They sure know how
to get their kicks.
- Why aren't you with them?
- [Tom] Oh, I don't know
how to get my kicks.
- That's why you stayed?
- [Joel] Yeah,
somethin' like that.
- Like with my little
fish, I was afraid
I wasn't going to see you again.
I'm glad I was wrong.
- Join us.
- [Crow] Join the party
and we will rule ze world!
- How 'bout it?
- [Tom] Well, I'm kinda
cooped out about that little
fish and everything.
It's all hot and
it hurts and stuff.
- His name is Angelo.
- [Tom] And he's a Teenage
Mutant Ninja Turtle.
- And he's probably
looking for me right now.
He told me to wait
down at the pier.
- [Joel] Oh, he said
somethin' about take a long,
short walk on a
long pier, or...?
- [Tom] Somethin' like that.
- [Crow] Hmm, it's a
dysfunctional relationship.
- I'd like to thank you.
- [Tom] I'd like to
thank the producers
and the directors too.
- Has he been gone long?
- No, not very.
- Don, would you like
to help me look for him?
- [Tom] I'll help
you, I'll help you!
- Down this way.
- [Tom] So, did you
call Harry Callahan yet?
- I'll need three more expert
divers by this time tomorrow.
- [Crow] And two implants.
- What are we divin' for?
- That's none of your business.
- [Joel] Well, how do we
know when we found it?
- You'd better get out of here.
- [Crow] Uh, like this?
- [Tom] Or like that?
(growling)
- [Tom] Now I'm going
to go polish my suit.
(laughing)
- [Tom] There she is again.
- You sure he came down here?
- Yes, he said he had to
meet a man on the beach.
- [Joel] Oh, that means he
has to go to the bathroom.
It's a guy thing.
- Oh, I think I'd better
go back and wait for him.
Angelo has such a bad temper.
- [Tom] Angelo Dundee?
- Katrina!
You dig this Angelo?
- We're going to be married.
- Not what I asked you.
- [Tom] Do you dig 'em?
- [Crow] I'm a
thousand feet tall.
- Katrina!
Why didn't you wait
like I told you to?
- Oh, you were
gone so long that--
- You still should have waited.
- She was worried.
- You keep outta this.
- Hey, cool it, man.
You're lookin' for trouble?
- Don, please.
Let me take care of this.
- All right.
But if you run any
static, just yell.
- [Joel] Just yell.
Call for the turtle boy.
- [Tom] Yeah.
- You were very rude, Angelo.
- You had no right to be on
the beach with a stranger.
- Angelo!
Something is very wrong.
Who is this man who paid
you for doing nothing?
And those men you
are always with?
- [Tom] Oh, he's from
paid programming.
This Carol Bennett thing isn't
gonna last forever, you know?
- I never shoulda brought
you here in the first place.
- [Crow] I shoulda
brought Vicky Lawrence.
- [Tom] Hmm?
What does that mean?
- Let us settle this
right here and now.
- [Crow] All right.
I'm all for it.
Hey, but we ran...
Hey!
- [Tom] Fade to black.
(laughing)
Okay, now Joel, how
do we comment on this,
without getting
into big trouble?
- [Joel] You can
use metaphor, maybe.
- [Tom] Oh, raspberry red.
- [Joel] Lemon yellow.
- [Tom] You've read my mind.
- [Joel] Choo-choo cherry.
- I just saw your sister.
- [Tom] D'oh!.
- [Joel] Oh I'm tired.
- [Crow] Quick, get a
pen down his throat.
Trache 'em.
- [Joel] He's tired
from all that make out.
- [Tom] Well, I don't
even have an agent.
I just saw the trade
dailies and here I am.
- [Joel] Hey, clambake.
- Fade out, man.
- [Joel] Fade out?
- Who's minding the store?
- [Tom] Jerry Lewis.
- Where'd you split to?
- Felt like cutting
out for a while.
- [Tom] Hmm, and
using a lot of jargon.
- Hi Bob.
- [Crow] Hi Netgirl.
- You like this suit?
- [Tom] Hmmmm, nyet.
- Wild!
- Don't you dare speak to me.
- [Tom] Okay.
- Wow!
- [Tom] It's her again!
It's Creepy Girl, oh.
- [Crow] Oh, forget her.
- [Tom] I can't.
I just can't.
- [Crow] Hi, lower life forms.
- Hello Don.
I've decided to accept
your invitation.
- [Joel] To the beheading?
- If it's still open.
- Aaahhh, it isn't.
- Sam, you've got to be
the mother of all pigeons.
- [Tom] Yeah, tell 'em to
stop messin' up our statues.
- Don't mind him.
He's got a language all his own.
- [Crow] Yeah, he
took a shell in 'Nam.
- Aren't you going
to introduce me
to your playmate, Don?
- Katrina, this is everybody.
- [Tom] Miss January,
this is everybody.
This is this.
- Katrina.
- That was real dandy, sport.
I'm Charlie Moss.
- [Joel] I collect
custom showgirls.
- But you can forget about him.
He's ready for a wheelchair.
- [Crow] Hey, come on!
I'm 17, Cut out the
good-natured ribbing.
- [Tom] Meet the
daughter of Satan.
- [Joel] I gotta
change my driftnet.
- Did I say something wrong?
- Where's Angelo?
- I don't know and
I don't really care.
- Because of me?
- That and a man
named Lakopolous?
- What about Lakopolous?
- [Crow] You'll thrash
her from top to bottomas.
- Diving, I think?
That's about the only
thing Angelo has ever done.
Why?
- Could that be the
diver you tangled with?
- [Tom] I dare not tell him
that they speak of my family.
- Who's Lakopolous?
- [Tom] I'll close
up his esophagus.
- Then you know
of his reputation.
- Afraid we do.
I wonder why Lakopolous
needs a diver?
- [Crow] I saw it on Techopolus.
- Help!
- [Joel] A baby's cry for help.
- [Tom] Help, my
career is drowning!
- Hang on, I'm coming.
- [Crow] Wait, I'll
get my jack...-
Oh no, I don't have it.
- [Tom] I'll stay here
and protect the heroin.
(laughing)
- [Joel] He's so funny
in the act of tragedy.
And I know it's
somethin' horrible.
- [Tom] Oh, there he goes.
- [Tom] Hey wait, he's
got salvage rights.
(dramatic orchestral music)
- [Joel] Now, was
that you who cried?
Keep her butt above
water, that's good.
- [Tom] Right, she's
better than that tarpon
I caught in Beamony.
It was a keeper.
I'm gonna get out
my fillet knife.
- [Crow] A little
surf and turf action.
- [Tom] You betcha.
(humming)
(mumbling)
- [Crow] Who saved...?
Why, the stinky guy?
(laughing)
- [All] She almost died.
- [Crow] She's got
water on her lungs.
Brain damage.
- And that's for
you, Moe and Larry.
Spinach chins.
- [Tom] D'oh!.
- You can bet if
she was drowning,
they would've all gone in.
- [All] Unite, unite, unite!
(barking)
- [Joel] Crazy
popper, crazy popper.
The slap-happiest game ever.
- [Tom] Hey, I
didn't get slapped.
- [Crow] Get 'em
girls, he hit Buddy.
This looks like a strange
version of Lysistrata.
- [Tom] Hmmmm-mmm.
(crowd mumbling)
(humming)
♪ The chicks are up in arms ♪
♪ They've left their
fields and barns ♪
♪ They're marching on the farm ♪
♪ Because the kids won't
drink enough milk ♪
- [Crow] I would.
♪ When you're a Jet, you're
a Jet all the way, hey ♪
♪ There ain't
nothin' like a dame ♪
♪ And get somethin'
on the side ♪
♪ Nothin' looks like a dame ♪
- [Joel] Now this
must be on the way to
the Greenwich Village
Halloween party.
I'm thinking.
- [Crow] I hope I get it.
I really hope I get it.
- [Tom] For some unexplicable
reason, a deep-seated
call from nature causes
these lemmings to follow
each other off the
edge of the high cliff.
- [Joel] Man, I
gotta pole with a...
Capital 'O'.
- [Tom] Whoo-hoo!
Is he a time-traveler?
- [Crow] And now Red
in the silent spot.
Red's a fisherman and...
- [All] Uh-oh.
(trolling in fishing rod)
- [Tom] Uh-oh.
- [Joel] Mmmmm.
Too small, you have
to throw it back.
(howling)
- [Crow] She hit Big Jake.
- [Tom] I feel a
number comin' on.
- Hey, we better do
something, but quick!
- Yeah, 'let's do somethin'.
- [Crow] Hey, it's
Gloria Estefan and the
Catalina deus-ex Soudmachina.
(upbeat techno-pop)
(trumpet music)
(drums)
- [Tom] Hey gang!
Maybe if we do
this, it'll be okay.
Ready?
Five, six, seven, eight!
- [Joel] He's the only
professional dancer they hired,
so they gotta use him.
- [Crow] Cassy!
(trumpet music)
- [Tom] Is that Deney Terrio?
- [Joel] Yeah, he's
the guy who taught
John Travolta to dance.
Girls just can't resist
the frolicking vibes
of a hot guy.
- [Tom] Neither can I.
(funky trumpet music)
Ooh, the body on him (laughs).
- [Crow] The girls begin
to become aroused by
the provocative gyrations of the
shamed males of the village.
(funky trumpet music)
- [Joel] You know, I still
am havin' a hard time
figuring out what this
has to do with any scroll.
- [Tom] I dunno.
- [Crow] Oh, yeah!
- [Tom] Hey gang, let's gather
around for the next scene!
- [Crow] Hey, it's the same
shot as before, I love that.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Continuity
gets into this one.
(funky trumpet music)
- [Joel] Wow, they're
dancing for Apartheid.
- [Tom] Yeah, it's to raise
money for the National Front.
- [Crow] It's the "Keep
Mandela in Prison" dance.
- [Tom] All right.
- [Joel] They wanna
play Sun City, guess.
- [Tom] PW Botha,
back in office.
- [Crow] Aaah, the
clean smell of kids
who know they rule the world.
(funky trumpet music)
- [Tom] Grab that lace, will ya?
- [Joel] Oh.
- [Tom] Too bad.
- [Joel] Next time.
(funky trumpet music)
- [Tom] I'm gettin' down.
- [Crow] Oops, sounds
like the tape's
getting eaten here.
- [Joel] Oops.
- [Tom] Oh, hmmm.
- [Crow] Eight-track.
Uhm, you wanna tie that
up over there, Servo?
- [Tom] I'm tryin'
to bite it there,
but my arms don't work.
Darn.
("Book of Love"
by Carol Connors)
♪ And her name is Sibyl ♪
♪ And all her friends ♪
- [Tom] Hey, this is great.
You know, now that she's
so famous, it's fun
to see these old clips, huh?
- [Crow] Yeah (laughing).
Who is she?
- [Joel] She went
on to obscurity.
- [Tom] Yeah, that's
a way to see things.
Boogie!
(laughing)
- [Crow] Hey, they grew up
to be Jim and Tammy Baker!
♪ Let's not have talent ♪
♪ Let's do away with fun ♪
♪ Let's all be white ♪
♪ Really, really white ♪
♪ Snowy white ♪
- [Crow] Hey, I checked out
the Book of Love one time,
and it was really hard
to find in the library,
'cause there's not a
lot of copies of it.
There's this note to the
margins and the pages--
Huh?
- [Joel] Shut 'em off.
Just watch the movie, okay?
♪ And we're all white ♪
♪ And we swing to the right ♪
- [Tom] Hey!
- [Crow] Here comes
Carmine Ragusa again.
- [Tom] Uh-oh.
- [Joel] How are ya, Sheol?
- [Crow] Hey, do the jerk!
The idiot!
The moron!
- [Tom] The
"potato-up-the-butt" dance!
The Dickweed!
- [Joel] Do the
white male reality!
The Donald Hellinger!
- [Tom] Yeah.
Do the back girl!
(funky music)
- [Joel] Yee-hoo!
- [Crow] It's just
one big, sunny,
fun-filled, Baton Death March.
- [Joel] Don't rewrite anything.
- [Crow] We never change.
Why should we?
We're on top of the world!
- [Tom] White love.
- [Joel] It's good, isn't it?
Tell me it's good, come on.
Get some swingin'.
- [Crow] Why did the Titanic
have to sink, and this didn't?
- [Joel] Irony.
You know what the difference is
between the Titanic and this?
- [Crow] What?
- [Joel] The Titanic
had talent (laughs).
- [Crow] Oh (laughs).
- [Tom] Thank you!
Thank you!
You've been a great
crowd, Catalina!
Tip your waitresses.
Good night everybody!
- [All] Oh (laughing)
- [Crow] Oh, the
old suitcase gag.
This is a classic.
- [Tom] Suitcase and a--
(laughing)
- [Crow] Oh yes,
that's so funny.
- [Tom] This guy
makes the film for me.
- [Joel] Yeah.
- [Crow] He makes a film
for me too, but it's--
- [Tom] Not this one, huh?
- [Crow] No.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Okay, let's can it.
The plot's back now.
- [Joel] A pasty film on the...
(clears throat)
- [Crow] The youth of today,
spent like so many shell casings
on the battlefield of love.
- Now remember, I'll
do all the talking.
- [Joel] And you do
the interpretive dance.
- Good man.
- Well, good morning everyone.
- [Crow] It was.
(laughing)
- I forgot.
- Hi, Mr. Duval.
- Ah, what a lovely day
for basking in the sun.
- What are you doing here, Dad?
- I just thought I'd take
my morning constitution.
- [Tom] Oh, here on the beach?
- At two in the afternoon?
(laughing)
- Can't fool you, can I son?
- No, but I've gotta a
feeling you're gonna try.
- [Tom] D'oh!
- Well, the truth of the matter
is I'm here for a reason.
You see, I'd like to do
something to put a little sing
in the weekend for you kids.
- [Crow] Might give you
some bennies, yellow jackets
or goofballs.
- What do you have in mind, Dad?
- How 'bout a
scuba diving party?
- Scuba parties are nothing new.
- [Tom] How 'bout Mickeys
and straightjackets
and nitrous oxide in the tanks?
- I want you and your
friends aboard my yacht
at 10 'o clock tomorrow morning.
How does that sound?
- Wild!
- [Crow] Yeah.
- And you'll be diving
for lost treasure.
Items towards five
dollars and up.
And here is the grand prize!
- [Joel] That's a
stick of dynamite!
You get to throw it at me.
- Oh, it's an old map case.
- [Crow] Now, for every
one of these you find,
we donate a penny
to Jerry's kids.
- And the diver who
brings this up, wins the
grand prize and one
hundred dollars.
- A hundred bucks?
- Wow, I could do with
a hundred dollars.
- [Tom] They're ain't
nothin' wrong with her
a hundred dollars couldn't fix.
- Don't forget!
On board by 10 'o clock!
- [Joel] And don't
forget your plot device.
- Dad, I've got that
funny feeling again.
- Take an aspirin, son.
- [Tom] Take a whole box.
- Okay, I'm with you so far.
But I'll be watching you, Dad.
- Good boy.
- [Joel] He's not
even my son, you know?
He's Marty Milner's kid.
- Well, the rest
is up to them now.
If they don't come
up with that scroll,
you can bet Lakopolous's
divers will.
- [Crow] Oh flog
notice crapulous.
- [Joel] Oh, there's no
way that guy can make
somethin' funny
outta that situation.
- [Tom] No.
Sister Act?
I don't see it, frankly.
- [Crow] He's a comic genius.
- [Joel] I don't see him--
(laughing)
- [Tom] Meanwhile, in Gotham's
Harbor, the Exxon Valdez.
- They should be coming up soon.
- [Crow] What, our lunch?
- They've been diving
for over an hour
and there's no case.
- Patience, Lawrence, patience.
- [Joel] Lawrence.
- [Tom] Hey everybody,
I found a new script.
And this one's funny.
- [Crow] Wow, there's
bobby pins down there
and Band-Aids and there's
a lotta hair in the drain.
- [Mr Duval] What do they got?
- [Tom] That what we ain't got.
- [All] Courage.
- Next divers.
- That's the third time they
come up with this thing.
- [Tom] You wanted to
see time fly (laughs)
- [Crow] Charlie
Sheen in "Navy Seals".
A Golan-Globus Production.
- [Joel] Hey, it's us again.
- Arthur, I have
a splendid idea.
Why don't they all go down
together for one final effort?
- [Tom] Without tanks.
- Sound idea.
Is that agreeable with everyone?
- [Joel] Very agreeable,
thanks for asking.
Appreciate it.
(suspenseful cello music)
- [Crow] We're here
to spoil everything.
- Over there!
- They must be
after the scrolls.
You see any other divers?
- [Tom] No, only you.
- We can't afford to guess.
Let's find out.
(suspenseful orchestra music)
- [Tom] Down here? Oh, okay.
- [Tom] Oh, there he is again!
(laughing)
- [Crow] This should be great.
- [Joel] Oh, this
must be a good one.
- [All] What?
- [Tom] Look, it's
Dino, Desi and Billy.
- [Crow] Hey, Sinatra
got 'em a gig.
- [Joel] At the
bottom of the harbor.
He must be tripping.
- [Crow] To entertain
all those other guys
at the bottom of the harbor.
- [Joel] Yeah.
- Lakopolous should have
made his move by now.
- Yeah well.
I guess they figured
we were just---
- [Tom] Hmm, they
got sandwiches.
Oh, wait!
They got that pistol
from "The Man from Glad".
- I really know how to
handle guys like that.
- Oh.
- You got me.
- Where is it?
- You're a very sneaky man.
- Oh, I'm with you.
- I don't have time
to fool around.
Where's the scroll?
- Should we give
him three guesses?
- I don't see why we should.
- Oh, don't make
him mad, don't--
- [Tom] Oh we gotta split, guys.
- [Crow] I can't watch this.
- [Tom] Oh they look tough!
(numberous doors closing)
- Oh man.
Oh I think it's a sarcasm
sequence or its a...
I'm gonna have to field
strip you, little buddy.
Come here.
- Ow, that hurt,
gimme that back.
- Hey neat!
I'd like a wing, please.
- The overlords are calling.
Look sharp, you guys.
- Oh hi, Joel.
Just thought you'd like
to see what we got goin'
on down here.
I think you know everybody.
This is Jerry and that's
Sylvia and you know
Joel and the Bots, so
let's get started and...
Oh Jerry, you haven't even
touched your sandwich.
It's good stuff.
And Sylvia, coffee?
Just all you want.
Free refills (laughs).
Anyw...
Oh, we're gonna
have a lot of fun.
Uh, so let's get started.
We've got fun, easy
to plant stuff here.
Now, Sylvia, back me up on...
You know what I'm
talkin' about, this one.
Are you with me on this?
These guns that are stored
under water this method
with the baggy and the...
It makes no sense, it's
totally impractical.
It's just outmoded stuff,
we have nothing to do with.
But this product, that I'm
giving you the opportunity
to get in on here...
It's a triple ply,
poly-carbonate,
reinforced substrate.
As a matter of fact, its
the type of material used
by the astronauts on
"It's About Time".
- Hey, Fred?
- Fred, how's our
new venture goin'?
- Uh, Frank, Frank.
- Oh, whatever.
- Oh well, it's uh...
- Don't mind me, I'm just
going to sit in and observe.
- Okay.
- Go on with your presentation.
- Okay, good.
You should get some of that...
I think we got some
Wisconsin cheese log there.
We've got the same
thing with ham.
Okay, uh, we got, uh...
Oh this is, uh, for
storing, uh, hand grenades.
It's perfect, it fits on...
And we have the gel in it
that stores it for you.
And look, it fits perfectly.
(nervous laughter)
Okay, and we have the, uh...
This salad...
This fruit salad
stays perfectly well.
Never would...
(nervous laughter)
Here, let me just, just take...
Put that there and...
This is even better, here.
This will stay right on there.
There's no...
(nervous laughter)
Hang on, we'll put the...
Oh, maybe I should do a joke.
You ever notice how the
Moleman with the thing and...
Coffee with the...
- Frank, Frank, Frank.
Why don't you just
pack it all in here.
It's okay.
Why don't we just
start cleaning up.
I...
(groans)
I give you points for your
little party here, but--
- You're gonna hurt
me, aren't you?
- No, Frank, I give you a--
- You're gonna be mean to me!
- No, I'm not.
Why do you pull away?
- You're gonna be mean.
You're gonna hurt me and
it's gonna be humiliating
and it's gonna hurt and stuff.
- Look, Frank, you've got
a lot to learn about being
a mad scientist
and you know, I...
I think I'll buy one
of your melon ballers.
- Oh, actually there's
some melon right up there.
- Frank!
(nervous laughter)
- Frank's going to be
having a little pain.
We'll be right back.
(screaming)
(Upbeat techno-pop)
(suspenseful violin music)
- Oh no, Charlie!
- [Crow] Oh my Karate pinky.
- [Joel] I've got the implant.
This will launch my empire.
(suspenseful orchestra music)
- [Tom] Oh, tell
your friends, dude.
- [Joel] Oh black
water, keep on rolling.
(suspenseful orchestra music)
- [Tom] Any resemblance
to a real action sequence
is purely coincidental here.
- Arthur!
- [Joel] Once you get
caught between the moon
and New York City...
- Did they get the case?
- Oh yes, I saw them take
it away from Charlie.
- [Crow] They took
my thumbs, they...
Oh, no wait, they're still here.
- What's in that case?
- Whatever it was,
it sure must've
been worth a lot of breaths.
- I knew you were
up to something.
I wanna know,
what's it all about?
- [Joel] Alfie.
- Fighting?
- I'd like an explanation
too, Mr. Duval.
I mean this is the second
time in the last few days
that I almost got myself killed.
- [Crow] Yeah, and lots
of other stuff too.
- Maybe if you take us
back to Avalon, son.
I'll explain a little later.
- Will you put your
hands down, Lawrence.
- [Tom] D'oh!, I don't
wanna play patty cake.
- Well, we really
shouldn't feel too badly.
The fates were against us.
- And it cost us
half a million bucks.
- [Joel] You know, I don't
think I wanna live in a world
filled with adults anymore.
Nothin's right.
- [Tom] You're hurting.
- Yeah, that's
what I'm afraid of.
- There's always the chance
of the police tracing
the stolen scroll
back to my folks.
- Are you sure this
is a real scroll?
- [Tom] Hey, who's
to say what's real
and what's not real, man?
- And besides, we heard
Dad talking about it.
- [Crow] We can thank the
screenwriter for that.
- The scroll we thought
we were diving for
was a phoney.
- I just got a flash.
- [Tom] A hot flash.
Whose going through menopause?
- Once they find out
that they've got the
wrong merchandise,
man, they're gonna
be out for blood.
- [Joel] Man, everything's
comin' down on me today.
- Let's unload the hot
potato on the fuzz.
- Cool it!
Get the fuzz into this and
his folks end up in jail.
- [Crow] I can't use
this lingo anymore.
- [Joel] He's
totally psycypolis.
- Be my guest.
I haven't got the blood to
spare for those folks of yours.
- [Tom] You got the hair for it.
- That's no good.
The minute dad gets it back,
the temptation will
be too much for 'em.
- [Tom] And the Four
Tops and the Spinners.
- From my breath you shoulda
left it where you threw it,
instead of going back
to dive for it later.
- [Crow] Please, I implore you.
Shut up!
- I have no right to say this.
- [Joel] God, your
hair smells good.
- I know a way to scare
the larceny out of your
folks once and for all.
- [Tom] Scare the what?
- And get Angelo
and Borman arrested.
- I'm ready to try anything
as long as it doesn't
involved Mother and
Dad with the police.
- [Crow] Or farm animals.
- We know they would
want the real scroll.
What we've gotta do is
make sure that they know
that we've got it.
- I'm not about to
have them take out
their frustrations on me!
- [All] Oh, shut up!
- And lose my image?
- [Tom] What image?
- What's the play?
- [Joel] Ah, it's Twelfth Night.
- We try and smoke
out Angelo and Borman.
Bound to be around
here someplace.
Let's find Tina and
some of the kids.
- [Crow] These kids today
with their loud music
and hula hoops and
fax machines...
I don't know.
For those of you following
along in the Syd Field
Screenplay workbook, that
last scene was the plot point,
setting up the third act.
Now this.
- [Tom] Mayberry.
After Hours.
- [Crow] No shirt,
no shoes, no script.
(laughing)
- [Joel] Okay.
Hello Muddah, hello Fadduh.
Here I am at, uh, Catalina.
(suspenseful music)
- [Tom] Zack Norman is
Sammy in Chief Zabu.
- [Crow] Uh-oh.
- [Joel] It's the big guy.
(suspenseful music)
- [Crow] I have to sit like
this since the implant.
- [Joel] I'm watching
you, crayon-head.
- [Tom and Joel] Ouch, oi,
ouch, ow, hot, hot, hot.
Asphalt, oh, oh, hot hot.
- Any luck?
- Nothing.
Here come the bunnies.
Maybe they did better.
- [Joel] Hoppin'
down the bunny trail.
- [Crow] Hey, it's Charlie's
Angels, plus a smart one.
- Nobody.
At least not anybody
who looks like the
two of you both on the Lyra.
- Keep looking.
- Move out, crew.
- [Joel] Oh it's McMillan
and wife and wife and wife.
- Don, can I talk
to you a minute?
- What?
- Huck, just a minute.
- We gotta go.
What's wrong?
- [Tom] I'm pregnant.
I'm sorry I slapped you.
And I wasn't really
drowning either.
- [Crow] Oh yeah
and I'm not acting.
- Really?
Really, but you do pack
a pretty mean wallop--
- Don't rub it in.
- I was gonna say
for a pretty girl.
- [Tom] Uh, but you're ugly.
- This Charlie Moss has
got a groovy sister.
And you know who else thinks so?
- [Joel] The football team?
- Tad.
- Well, I apologized to him too.
Only first...
It's them!
- Go find Charlie, quick!
- [Tom] Right now.
- [Joel] Hey Charlie.
I take 'em on, I know
I can, I'll do it.
I will, I will, I will.
(upbeat techno-pop)
(suspenseful orchestra music)
(humming)
- [Crow] Hmm, lucky.
Open table.
(suspenseful orchestra music)
- [Joel] How come he
got a menu already?
- [Tom] Lucky.
(spurt)
- [Tom] Oh peach daiquiri.
So that's what I
drank last night.
- [Crow} Nice Bit Tank, Dude.
(suspenseful violin music)
- [Crow] I'm still waiting
for my spinach omelet.
- And no slip-up this time.
- Hi.
- [Joel] Yes I am, and you?
- I've been looking for you.
- [Tom] Creepy Girl!
- Don't make any heroic
moves, my friend.
- [Tom] It's too late
to rewrite the script!
- Hand it over.
- Angelo, what are
you doing here?
- [Crow] Workin', bein' evil.
Shut up!
- I don't have time for games.
- [Tom] And I haven't
got time for the pain.
- Angelo!
- [Joel] Man, everybody's
comin' down on Angelo.
(suspenseful cello music)
- Thank you.
- [Tom] Creep.
(suspenseful orchestra music)
- [Joel] After him, team gang!
(laughing)
- [Tom] D'oh!, ooh!
When you're a Jet,
you're a Jet all the way.
- Splendid, son.
- [Crow] It's a
Catalina Army Knife.
- Always be prepared.
- [Joel] And effeminate.
We'll take care of the
garbage, go get 'em, Don..
- Can you handle
this for Mr Duval?
- [Joel] It's land fuzz.
- [Tom] Some call
them land pigs.
- You Bunnies stay here.
Duty calls your master away.
- [Crow] What do
you mean by that?
- [Tom] Okay people.
Everybody wear eye protection.
There's a lotta loose
ends flyin' together
all at once here.
- [Crow] Wow, this Main
Street U.S.A. parade
is really gettin' thin.
- [Tom] Oh, hi folks!
- [Crow] That's not
Mickey, that's Nicky.
- [Joel] Hey, he's running
into the haunted mansion, ooh.
- [Tom] I'm your ghost host.
- [All] Ouwie, ouch,
ouch, ouch, owie, ouch.
- [Crow] Pratfall anyone?
Pratfall, I got 'em all.
- [All] Ouwie, ouch,
ouch, ouch, owie, ouch.
- [Crow] Hmmmm, no
exit through there.
- [Tom] All right,
come on, come on!
(punching)
(incoherent babbling)
- [Joel] Don't snag on
me, don't snag on me!
- [Tom] Eat it, boy, eat it!
- [All] Oh no!
(incoherent babbling)
- [All] Woooooowwww.
(splash)
(mimicking incoherent
babbling under water)
- [Crow] You got
me all wet, boy.
- [Tom] Well, I guess he's
swimming back to Greece.
(suspenseful orchestra music)
- [Joel] A little
late, aren't you buddy?
- [Joel] Take a rest, friend.
You've provided
enough comic relief.
Thank you, Corky
the Water Clown,
for making us laugh at love...
Again.
- What do you
think you're doing?
- I've got you this time, Duval.
- Will you take these
silly things off my wrist?
- [Crow] I'm the silly thing.
- I've waited a long time
for you to make a slip
and now I've got ya!
- What's this all about?
Who are you?
- Fingers O'Toole.
- [Tom] F.B.I,
Pratfall Division.
- And what's the charge?
- Grand theft.
- [Joel] And wearing an ascot.
- You don't even know
what you're talking about.
- You stole the scroll
from the collection.
And it's in that
case you're holding..
- [Joel] Oh wow,
he's holdin', dude.
- [Tom] Hey cool,
a Bon Jovi poster!
- [Joel] Kinda like a
pea shooter, isn't it?
- [Tom] Good one.
- It's gone!
- [Crow] My career!
- It was in there, I
know it was in there.
- [Joel] Why me?
Why me all the time?
- Where did it go?
I don't believe this.
- [Joel] I'm Iggy Pop, oh boy.
- [Tom] Hey, the
script's in Braille now.
He looks about 40.
- Closing time, young fella.
- [Crow] The guy who lives
here wants to go to bed.
- It sure is beautiful.
- Yeah, it sure is.
(marching music)
- [Joel] Man, I sure love
that old snot rag of a...
- [All] Huh?
(whistle blows)
- So, you don't win 'em all.
- [Tom] Oh, the pain, the pain.
Oh, stealing art.
Being thugs.
Shaving my head.
- I told you it would
be a long walk--
- [Crow] Didn't I tell you that?
- Enjoy.
- [Tom] You promiscuous,
meddling robot monster.
Kill him, kill him!
- [Joel] Hmmmm, musical
newspaper from Japan.
- [Tom] And look!
Zack Norman as
Sammy in Chief Zabu.
(upbeat saxophone music)
- [Crow] Uh, eh let's
quit, I'm hemorrhaging.
- [Joel] Hey, Mom, Dad,
you got any rhythm left?
We're out.
- How, how did it
get out of my case
and back into the museum?
- [Tom] Go figure.
- As Charles would say,
"Don't knock 'em dead".
Perhaps it's best
forgotten anyway.
Lakopolous has
sailed away forever.
Perhaps he'd leave
here wiser too, period.
- [Joel] I doubt it.
- There's only one answer, Anne.
Somebody up there likes us.
- No dear, I think
someone loves us.
- [Crow] Well, it's not me.
- Well, what now?
What's left for us?
- [Joel] Drug running?
Prostitution?
Slumlords?
- Well, you could
always go to work.
- Yeah...
Work?!
As Charles might say,
that's a boss idea.
You know, it's time
I did some retiring?
- [Joel] Or there's that
Louis Nai look-alike contest.
Yeah, dance, goosey.
(funky saxophone music)
- [Tom] Oh I've outgrown
this pratfall stuff.
It was just a phase.
Now I'm a swingin' cat, yeah!
- [Crow] Hey, it's a skinhead.
Get Geraldo.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Oh look at Creepy Girl!
Doesn't she look great
in that hairdo like that?
I like her in a flip.
- [Joel] Oh he's down
to one girl, huh?
He's cuttin' back.
Oh nobody wants to dance
with the big, stinky guy.
- [Tom] Shirt's louder
than the music, isn't it?
- [Joel] Yeah.
- [Tom] Aaahhh, dork shack.
- [All] Dork shack, baby, yeah.
- [Tom] It's where it's at.
- [Joel] Got a movie
that's as long as a whale!
- [Tom] It's about
to set sail, whoo!
- [Crow] A plot hole
that's as big as a whale.
- [Tom] Huzzah! King John
invites you to the Ren Festival.
Come see 300 years
crammed in one place.
Meet the people you
snagged on in high school.
Bring your own tights
or wear some of our own.
- [Crow] Ah, principals
to the front, please.
Extras in back.
There you go, thank you.
- [Joel] Oh it was only a movie.
- [Tom] What?
Aaaaahhh.
It wasn't real?
Well it was real too.
- [Crow] Wait, I'm
havin' some trouble here.
- [Joel] I was right
in the middle of that.
- [Crow] Oh brother.
So bad.
- [Joel] A good movie deserves
a good encore of the cast.
- [Tom] I wonder if we're
gonna see the fish again
here at the end.
- [Crow] What fish?
- [Crow] Oh, that's right.
- [Tom] The fish from
the beginning, you know?
- [Crow] And the scroll...
That was good.
- [Joel] I still don't
really get what happened.
- [Crow] Uhm...
- [Tom] We gotta do
somethin' to understand this.
This was just bizarre.
Where did the scroll
go to and how did it
get back to where it was?
- [Joel] This is harder than a
Werner Herzog film
to figure out.
- [Crow] I think it's
important that we experienced
it together, don't you?
And we shared.
- [Joel] Yeah, we
gotta get outta here.
- [Tom] Yeah, let's go.
AMF vomit?
- [Crow] Carry me.
- [Tom] Oh, that's Voit.
- [Crow] No, please, come on.
(numerous doors closing)
- Man, that was really a
confusing movie, wasn't it?
- Well no, uhm, not really.
I only have one
question, actually.
- And what's that, Crow?
- What the Sam
Hill was goin' on?
- Yeah.
- Well, which part
of the movie did you
have a hard time with?
- Well I was doin' okay until
the opening credits ended
and then I thought
it was like a cartoon
with really good animation.
- You know, I'm confused too.
The only thing that made
any sense to me was that
darling Creepy Girl.
I can't seem to get
her out of my mind.
♪ Ooooohhhhhh ♪
♪ Yah, yah, yah, yahaaaaaaaaa ♪
- Uh, Tom, Tom.
♪ My Creepy Girl,
My Creepy Girl ♪
- [Joel] Stop the music.
Cambot, cut it out.
- Oh sorry.
- Very good, Mr Tommy
Servotune there.
I had a feeling this was
gonna happen with this,
so on the way back from the
theater on the spiral and, uhm--
Will you just move
over, you guys?
I took the liberty of making
this chart of the film, okay?
So we could figure
out a lot better.
- Oooh, neat!
- Yeah, great, thank you.
You spinach chins.
Anyway, this is gonna
make us all feel better.
So, let me just
start explaining it
and we can help each other.
Okay, act one.
The Alan Sherman wannabe
in the Crayola Hat...
That's this guy down here...
Steals the scroll from...
Pegboard Mansion...
Okay, Tom?
- Uh, oh, oh
And he hands it off to
the Louis Nai guy...
The Billy De Wolfe wannnabe
with the Jim Backus mouth.
And the upgrade wife aboard
the thinnest ship in the navy.
- Oh, I remember now.
Upgrade wife threw a fake
of it, which they planned
to pawn off on Mr. Vanapolis.
- Yeah.
- Okay, slam dance cosmpolis--
- Do the wormacropolis.
- Would you two stopolis?
(laughing)
- Okay, then Lockjaw,
Jim Backus and
Crayola head here, get
in a big, plastic castle
with Lyle Waggoner and the
script or the scroll ends up
goin' south by the fish.
- Hold on, Joel.
You're gettin' way
ahead of yourself.
What about Tommy Kirk
meeting the Creepy Girl
on the boat and the
sensitive soliloquy about
the little fishy?
- Oh wow, wait a
minute, wait a minute.
You're both forgetting to
mention that all the singing
and dancing with Little Richard
tripped up on goofballs.
- What the heck did that
have to do with anything?
The entire plot was hinged
on the relationship between
the Creepy Girl and Tommy Kirk.
- No, listen.
The whole emotional thrust
of the second act was when
Lockjaw throws the
hullabaloo-come-treasure hunt
to get the scroll back
in his possession.
- No, wait, what about the
dysfunctional relationship
that the kid who looked
like Jim Baker...
You know, come on.
Shared with Billy De
Wolfe and Jane Bennett?
I thought that was the
emotional center of the film.
- If anything, Crow, that
was the emotional tootsy
center of the film.
(groaning)
Man, I'm p'd off.
I'm gonna go get the letters.
- Uh, Joel, Joel, Joel.
The letters are right
here on the desk.
- Read out loud, will 'ya?
- Yeah, I'll first
try to calm down.
- Okay.
Oh, this is great.
I'm sorry it got kinda
crazy there, but...
So am I.
Okay, this is a
really neat letter.
Let's put it up on the
screen there, Cambot.
It says, "Dear Joel,
Tom, Servo, Gypsy,
Cambot and of course, Crow,
We think this may be
a first for your show.
We met, we spent time
together and fell in love
Watching MST3K and now
we're getting married."
- Awwww, that's wonderful.
- "We're hoping you can make
it to the nuptual festivities,
but if the evil scientist
won't let you guys out,
please send a picture of Crow
for us to keep and cherish
as a precious reminder."
- Awwww.
- "Tell Crow that door is ajar."
And here...
Put this up, Cambot.
Here's the wedding announcement.
We're gonna have to black
out some of this so--
- Like their names.
we don't get a bunch
of misties there.
But anyway--
- [Crow] It's the Trumps
and it's in New York.
(laughing)
- Is it an open bar?
- I think that was super cute,
cool and really romantic.
- Yeah, isn't romance wonderful?
Hit it, Cambot!
♪ Whooo-hoooooo Creepy Girl ♪
Oh, Creepy Girl, my
eyes pour out to you
in heaves and droves
of iridescent shapes
and stars through the sky.
But I don't care, Creepy Girl.
I got hit in the
head with crowbar
and I just don't see
straight anymore.
All I know is, I love you.
- Bad movie.
- Good fruit salad.
Push the button, Martha Stewart.
(incoherent singing)
(click)
(slow music)